Guide to the Winsor Dana Ireland student notebooks, 1926-1935.
Ireland, Winsor Dana student notebooks
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Winsor Dana Ireland student notebooks, 1926-1935.
37-5-4217
Ireland, Winsor Dana
2
Manuscripts, Research Materials
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Collection includes a nearly complete set of notebooks for Ireland's coursework at Cornell.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Winsor D. Ireland graduated Cornell in Fall of 1935 with a B.S. in Agriculture. He was a member of Phi Kappa Tau. Before coming to Cornell he attended East High School in Rochester.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Collection includes a nearly complete set of notebooks for Ireland's coursework at Cornell. Extensive lecture and laboratory notes, papers, examinations, lab exercises, field notes, syllabi and other assignments, both the printed tasks and test papers as well as the completed work. Collection covers a variety of subjects with a focus on agriculture, agricultural engineering, and dairy industry. Also included is one chemistry notebook from East High School.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Ireland, Winsor Dana 1909-1995 .; Cornell University -- Students.; Cornell University. Class of 1935.; Cornell University. College of Agriculutre.; New York State College of Agriculture.
Subjects:
Agricultural engineering -- Study and teaching.; Agricultural mechanics -- Study and teaching.; Bacteriology -- Study and teaching.; Biology -- Study and teaching.; Botany -- Study and teaching.; Chemistry -- Study and teaching.; Dairying -- Study and teaching.; Economics -- Study and teaching.; English -- Study and teaching.; Entomology -- Study and teaching.; Forestry -- Study and teaching.; Geology -- Study and teaching.; Meteorology -- Study and teaching.; Music -- Study and teaching.; Physics -- Study and teaching.; Psychology -- Study and teaching.; Vegetables -- Study and teaching.; Wildlife Conservation -- Study and teaching.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- East High School Rochester Chemistry Notebook, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Instructors included Helma C. Russell and Burr F. VVilliams.
- Botany 1, General Botany, Fall 1931 - Spring 1932 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Instructor names are not given in the notebooks, but using the course announcements a potential instructor is listed. Possible instructor: Ruth Alice Petry
- Geology 100, Introduction to Geology, Fall 1931 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Possible instructor: Ries, Burfoot, Megathlin, Von Englin
- English 1, Elementary Composition and Literature, Fall 1931 - Spring 1932 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Possible instructor: Baldwin, Muller, Harris, Adams
- Agricultural Engineering 21, Farm Engineering, Fall 1931 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  Possible instructor: John Clarence McCurdy
- Geology 101, Selected Problems in Geology, Spring 1932 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  Possible instructor: Charles Merrick Nevin
- Chemistry 101, Introductoray Inorganic Chemistry, Spring 1932 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Possible instructor: Arthur Wesley Browne, Albert Washington Laubengayer
- Agricultural Engineering 1, Farm Mechanics & 24 Farm Concrete, Fall 1932 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  Possible instructor: Howard Wait Riley and John Clarence McCurdy
  Covers a wide range of gas engine and electrical repairs
- Animal Biology 303, Human Physiology, Fall 1932 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  Possible instructor: Joseph Alma Dye
- Music 1, Theory and Practice of Music, Fall 1932 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  Possible instructor: Andrew Comstock Haigh
- Rural Social Organization 1, Introduction to Sociology, Fall 1932 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  Possible instructor: Walfred Albin Anderson
- Chemistry 210, Introductory Qualitative Analysis, Spring 1933 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  Possible instructor: Alfred William Avens
- Rural Education 110, Psychology: An Introductory Course, Spring 1933 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  Possible instructor: Andrew Leon Winsor
- Dairy 1, Introductory Dairy Science, Spring 1933 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  Possible instructor: Barbour Lawson Herrington and Menalco Solis
- Vegetable Crops 1, Vegetable Crops, Spring 1933 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  Possible instructor: Paul Work
- Wildlife Conservation 1, The Conservation of Wild Life, Fall 1933 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  Possible instructor: James George Needham, Ralph Sheldon Hosmer, Karl McKay Hosmer, and others
- Entomology 12, General Entomology, Fall 1933 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  Possible instructor: Glenn Washington Herrick
- Animal Husbandry 1, Livestock Production, Fall 1933 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  Possible instructor: Merritt Wesley Harper, Elmer Seth Savage and others
- Dairy Industry 103, Milk Products Manufacturing, Fall 1933 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  Possible instructor: Edward Sewall Guthrie
- Entomology 41, General Economic Entomology, Spring 1934 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Dairy Industry 104, Milk Products Manufacturing, Spring 1934 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  Possible instructor: Winfred Enos Ayres
  Includes information on condensed milk, ice cream, pasteurization, chocolate
- Agricultural Engineering 101, Electricity no the Farm, Spring 1934 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  Possible instructor: Forrest Blythe Wright
- Economics 1, Modern Economic Society, Spring 1934 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  Possible instructor: Paul Martin O'Leary
- Physics 3, Introductory Experimental Physics, Fall 1934 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  Possible instructor: Harley Earl Howe
- Vegetable Crops 12, Grading and Handling Vegetable Crops, Fall 1934 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Meteorology 1, Elementary Meteorology, Fall 1934 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  Possible instructor: Richard Alan Mordoff
- Agricultural Economics 171, History of Agriculture, Fall 1934 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  Possible instructor: George Nieman Lauman
- Bacteriology 1, General Bacteriology, Fall 1934 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  Possible instructor: Clifford Nicks Stark
- Physics 4, Introductory Experimental Physics, Spring 1935 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Agricultural Engineering 102, Farm Power MAchinery, Spring 1935 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  Possible instructor: Frank Latta Fairbanks
- Music 5, The Art of Music, Spring 1935 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  Possible instructor: Paul John Weaver
- Dairy Industry 102, Market Milk and Milk Inspection, Spring 1935 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  Possible instructor: Harold Ellis Ross and Winfred Enos Ayres
  Includes field reports on milk quality and milk sample testing reports.
- Forestry 1, The Farm Woodlot & 3, Conservation of Natural Resources, Spring 1935 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  Possible instructor: Cedric Hay Guise and Bristow Adams
- Geography S1, Physical Geography, S8, Physical Geography Laboratory Course & S10, Geography and Geology Field Course, Summer 1935 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  Possible instructor: Oscar Diedrich Von Engeln, Louis Cowles Conant
  Includes papers on the formation of gorges in the Ithaca area, the physiographic history of Cornell, Niagara Falls and gorge, geology of Portland Point, Northern Pennsylvania, glaciers
- Miscellaneous folder (Box 2, Folder 15)
  Includes bill for Phi Kappa Tau fraternity and also a copy of his transcript showing his classes. The folders in the collection have been organized mostly as they appear on this transcript.